calgary.ca 2017-06-25

# The City of Calgary - Calgary.ca privacy statement

The City of Calgary is committed to providing a website that respects your privacy. This statement summarizes the privacy policy and practices on the calgary.ca website and all associated systems, processes and applications under the direct control of The City of Calgary. The City of Calgary is subject to [Alberta’s Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy (​FOIP) Act](http://www.servicealberta.ca/foip/).

## Privacy​​ overview

**The City of Calgary (The City) does not automatically gather any personal information from you.** This information is only obtained if you supply it voluntarily through contacting The City via email or online forms or by setting up a user account. 

When you visit calgary.ca, The City’s web server automatically collects a limited amount of standard information essential to the operation and evaluation of The City’s website. This information includes:

  * the page from which you arrived,
  * the date and time of your page request,
  * the Internet Protocol (IP) address your computer is using to receive information,
  * the type and version of your browser, and
  * the name and size of the file you requested.

**This information is not used to identify individuals who come to The City’s website**. This information is only used to help The City assess its information services and is collected in compliance with Section 33 (c) of Alberta’s Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy (FOIP) Act.

## Information Collected ​through the Feedback Forms or Service Requests

The personal information you submit through The City’s Customer Feedback Forms – including email address and contact information – is collected by The City’s Customer Service and Communications team solely for the purpose of responding to your information or service request.

**​This information is not disclosed except to authorized personnel (City staff or Contractors) for the purpose of addressing your feedback.** Any personal information you submit to The City is secured once it reaches The City’s server. However, The City cannot guarantee the security of your information before it reaches The City’s server.

## Cookies

Cookies are temporary files that may be placed on your hard drive while you visit a website. Cookies are used to track how visitors use calgary.ca, but The City does not store personal information through cookies, nor does The City collect personal information from you without your knowledge as you browse this website. Any cookies on calgary.ca are used to aid in the collection of anonymous statistical information such as:

  * browser type
  * screen size,
  * traffic patterns,
  * pages visited.

This information helps The City improve both calgary.ca and its service to citizens. It is not disclosed to any third parties. However, if you are concerned about cookies, you can adjust your web browser to reject all cookies. All site features with the exception of the interac​tive map should function normally if cookies are disabled.

## Security and​ IP addre​sses

Your computer uses a unique IP address when browsing the Internet. The City may collect IP addresses to monitor any security breaches on calgary.ca and other online services. No attempt is made to identify users or their usage patterns unless unauthorized use of The City’s website is detected or is required for a law enforcement investigation. IP addresses are stored for a term that complies with The City’s existing auditing requirements.

## Privacy and E​xternal Links

The calgary.ca website contains links to external sites that are not associated with The City. The City is not responsible for the content and the privacy practices of these other websites and The City encourages you to examine each site's privacy policy and disclaimers before providing any personal information.

## More Information

If you do not feel comfortable completing our [Contact Us/Feedback form​](https://calgary-csrprodcwi.motorolasolutions.com/Public/ServiceRequest.mvc/SRIntakeStep2/CCCCCWEB) or to request more information, please contact The City’s 311 service.

​For general inquiries regarding The City's customer feedback forms and associated privacy statement, contact: | Concerns regarding access to information or privacy issues under FOIP should be directed to:​  
---|---  
Director, Customer Service and Communications (CSC)  
​The City of Calgary  
800 Macleod Trail  
Calgary, AB T2P 2M5  
Phone: 3-1-1 or 403-268-CITY (2489) if calling from outside Calgary. | ​​FOIP Coordinator  
The City of Calgary  
P.O. Box 2100  
Calgary, AB T2P 2M5  
Phone: 403-476-4100  
Fax: 403-476-4101  
  
You can also view [the Government of Alberta's Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy (FOIP) Act​](http://foip.gov.ab.ca/).
